Guide to the Joseph Brodsky Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material, 1953-2002; Series VII; 5.53; (15 boxes)
  - Audio Material
    - Other recordings
      - [Aleksandr] Kushner interview and poetry, undated; 1; 00:59:39; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392176)
      - D. Shostakovich. Vocal works. Includes "Seven poems of A. Blok", undated; 1; 01:33:43; Static, clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392184)
        Material, written in Russian, came with this audiocassette. It is housed in Box 170 folder 3757.
      - Il'ia Shustarovich, undated; 1; 00:43:52; The program is distorted at times. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392192)
        An envelope that came with this audiocassette is housed in box 170, folder 3758.
      - Jelena Milisic, on the death of her husband [Milou?], Croatian PEN Centre, undated; 1; 00:00:34 (Box 232, Item barcode 39002104508966)
        An envelope came with this audiotape reel. It is kept in box 170, folder 3759.
      - From the Jazz Club "Kvadrat", undated; 1; 01:01:00; High frequency background noise can be heard from 30:31 until the end of the tape. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392200)
      - "Niotkuda s liuboviu," Romances and songs of Igor [Egikii?], undated; 1; 01:24:51; The program is distorted at times. Static can be heard. Audio is at a low level on the right channel from 35:40-41.12. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392218)
      - Jelena i ryska poeters sallskap. Watersound music, undated; 1 (Box 169, Folder 3738)
      - Billie Holiday, Commodore Records (phonograph record), undated; 1
    - Unidentified recordings
      - Analysis of the poetry of Kline/ Orpheus, Eurydice, Hermes, 1980 January 4, 1980 March 27; 1; 01:33:14; Static can be heard on the tape. The right channel of audio was recorded at a low level for much of the first 46 minutes. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392226)
      - "Joseph A. Brodsky", 1996 March 8; 1; 01:00:54; High background noise can be heard on the tape. High frequency noise is heard throughout the program. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392234)
      - Unlabeled in envelope sent from Margaret Kirby, undated; 1; 00:07:45; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392242)
        Audio fan letters to Joseph Brodsky from Peggy Kirby, a self-described blind woman in her 70s.
      - Unlabeled, undated; 1; 01:33:19; Static can be heard on the tape. Content on the tape contains high and low test tones. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392259)
      - Writer's block, relationships, undated; 1; 01:00:22; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392267)
      - "I.", undated; 1; 00:44:26; Audio was recorded at a low level on the right channel for the last 32 minutes of the tape. (Box 225, Item barcode 39002091392275)
  - Video Material
    - Recordings of Joseph Brodsky
      - In Oregon, 1976 November; GENMSS613_0003; 1; 00:21:24 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002102317709)
        From Lev Losev.
      - When I think of Russia. Mystic Fire Video., 1980; GENMSS613_0004; 1; 00:54:55 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002102318202)
      - When I think of Russia. Mystic Fire Video., 1980; 1; This is a duplicate. Only one was digitized. GENMSS613_0004 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002102317717)
      - American Broadcasting Company, "Russia", 1984 March 5; GENMSS613_0001; 1; 00:31:07 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002088212932)
      - American Broadcasting Company, 20/20, Voices, part 2, 1984 March 27; GENMSS613_0002; 1; 00:04:26 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002088212940)
      - Interview in Stockholm at the Nobel Ceremony, 1987 December 10; GENMSS613_0005; 1; 02:50:59 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002102317725)
      - On French television, 1988-1989; GENMSS613_0006; 1; 00:58:04 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002102317733)
      - With Seamus Heaney, Derek Walcott, and Wallace Shawn, 1988 February 15; GENMSS613_0007; 1; 01:40:40 (Box 171, Item barcode 39002102317741)
      - Poetry International Rotterdam. A film by Hand von Bruggen., 1989; GENMSS613_0008; 1; 00:26:11 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102318210)
      - Poetry International Rotterdam. A film by Hand von Bruggen., 1989; 1 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102317758)
      - Joseph Brodsky: Poet between empires, International Merchandising Corporation, 1990; 1 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102318228)
      - Joseph Brodsky: Poet between empires, International Merchandising Corporation, 1990; GENMSS613_0009; 1; 00:19:44 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102317766)
        Related Materials
        For related printed material, see box 242.
      - Fear and the muse: The story of Anna Akhmatova. WGBH, 1991; GENMSS613_0010; 1; 00:58:06 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102318236)
      - Fear and the muse: The story of Anna Akhmatova. WGBH, 1991; 1 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102317774)
      - Poetry reading, 1991 May 1; GENMSS613_0011; 1; 00:19:46 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102317782)
      - "Sunday Today," National Broadcasting Company, 1991 June; GENMSS613_0012; 1; 00:23:11; The tape stopped recording after the Brodsky segment. (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102317790)
      - On Anna Akhmatova, 1992; GENMSS613_0013; 1; 02:03:25 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102317808)
      - Rod MacLeish's Week, 1992 February 22; GENMSS613_0014; 1; 00:24:51 (Box 172, Item barcode 39002102317816)
      - On Nightline, 640, 1992 June 18; GENMSS613_0015; 1; 00:22:22 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102317824)
        Existence and Location of Copies
        Reference copy available.
      - A voice in exile. Claremont McKenna College., 1993 March 22; GENMSS613_0016; 1; 00:59:23 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102317832)
      - Joseph Brodsky, Fyra Ryska Poeter., 1993 April 6; GENMSS613_0017; 1; 00:48:21; There is a slight buzz in the audio from 00:05:07 until the end of the tape. (Box 173, Item barcode 39002102317840)
      - At Eckerd College, 1995 February 13; GENMSS613_0018; 1; 01:33:14 (Box 173, Item barcode 39002102317857)
      - Lecture at Draper Program for Liberal Studies, New York University, "The cat's meow," New York University, 1995 March 31; GENMSS613_0019; 1; 00:17:24 (Box 173, Item barcode 39002102317865)
      - United States of Poetry. Programs One-Three. KQED., 1996; GENMSS613_0020; 1; 01:30:40 (Box 173, Item barcode 39002102317873)
      - United States of Poetry. Programs Four-Five. KQED., 1996; GENMSS613_0021; 1; 00:54:37 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102317881)
      - Joseph Brodsky, by Birgitta Ashott. Giro Studio., undated; 1 (Box 173, Item barcode 39002102317899)
      - Joseph Brodsky, by Birgitta Ashott. Giro Studio., undated; GENMSS613_0022; 1; 00:43:46 (Box 173, Item barcode 39002102318244)
      - Joseph Brodsky: A maddening space. Mystic Fire Video., 1991; GENMSS613_0023; 1; 00:57:23 (Box 173, Item barcode 39002102317907)
      - Fassung [Russian version]. Wagner Elektronische Film- und Fernsehbearbeitung, undated; GENMSS613_0024; 1; 00:26:17; NTSC (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102317931)
      - Nobel Prize winners, 1997; GENMSS613_0025; 1; 00:39:44 (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102317949)
      - A stroll with Brodsky, undated; GENMSS613_0026; 1; 01:26:13 (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102317964)
      - A stroll with Brodsky, undated; 1; This is a duplicate of GENMSS613_26. It has not been digitized. (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102317972)
      - Joseph Brodsky and Seamus Heaney on the Charlie Rose Show, 1996; GENMSS613_0027; 1; 00:28:49 (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102317980)
    - Other recordings
      - Czeslaw Milosz: The poet remembers, 1990; GENMSS613_0028; 1; 00:59:31 (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102317998)
      - Soviet television, 1990 March 9; GENMSS613_0029; 1; 03:26:00 (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102318004)
      - How they joked at the Soviet Communist Party, directed by Aleg Gaisenok, 1992; GENMSS613_0030; 1; 00:34:33 (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102318012)
      - Joseph Brodsky Memorial, University of Oregon, Symposium Vladimir Utland and C. Surnyk, tape 1, 1996 May 24; GENMSS613_0031; 1; 01:20:53; The video quality of the tape is poor. (Box 174, Item barcode 39002102318020)
      - Joseph Brodsky Memorial, University of Oregon, Symposium Roman Timenchik and Andrei Ustinov, tape 2, 1996 May 24; GENMSS613_0032; 1; 01:18:30 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318038)
      - Joseph Brodsky Memorial, University of Oregon, tape 3, 1996 May 24; GENMSS613_0033; 1; 02:00:29 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318046)
      - Joseph Brodsky Memorial, University of Oregon, tape 4, 1996 May 24; GENMSS613_0034; 1; 00:43:14 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318053)
      - "Letters from the Ming Dynasty" (after Joseph Brodsky), undated; GENMSS613_0035; 1; 00:10:48 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318061)
      - The personal file of A. Akhmatova, a film by Semyon Aranovich. American Adaptation by Maryna Albert, undated; GENMSS613_0036; 1; 01:04:02 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318079)
      - "To Joseph: Happy New Year", undated; GENMSS613_0037; 1; 01:16:03 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318087)
        The beginning of the tape features 30 minutes of PM Magazine followed by a mostly inaudible series of people talking.
      - The Group on Joseph Brodsky, 1996; GENMSS613_0038; 1; 00:28:21 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318095)
        This is a WGBH production.
      - Buch des Monats, undated; GENMSS613_0039; 1; 00:42:45 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318103)
        An interview with Evgenii Rein on Brodsky.
      - "Bobo" and Brodsky., undated; 1; 00:41:26 (Box 175, Item barcode 39002102318111)
        There is a Russian, typewritten letter included with the videocassette.
    - Unidentified recordings
      - "D-04", undated; GENMSS613_0041; 1; 02:49:41 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318129)
      - "From nowhere with love," Al. Shishov, undated; GENMSS613_0042; 1; 00:43:28; A note attached reads: Second Venice film/return for archive (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318137)
      - Unlabeled TDK VHS cassette, undated; GENMSS613_0043; 1; 00:43:18 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318145)
      - "Brodsky Dub master" - "A Day in the Life of Joseph Brodsky", undated; GENMSS613_0044; 1; 00:50:30 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318152)
      - "2000 May 24", GENMSS613_0045; 1; 00:22:35 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318160)
      - "U samovara," directed by Aron Kanevskii, undated; GENMSS613_0046; 1; 00:43:18 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318178)
      - "JB", undated; GENMSS613_0047; 1; 00:28:58 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318186)
      - "Joseph", undated; GENMSS613_0048; 1; 00:13:14 (Box 176, Item barcode 39002102318194)
- Clippings, 1964-2002, undated; Series VIII; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  The Series is organized under two headings: Clippings related to Brodsky and Other Clippings. Material is arranged chronologically under each heading.
  Clippings related to Brodsky consists of newspaper and magazine articles that are directly about Brodsky or his writings. Articles include profiles, announcements and reviews of his writings. Other Clippings include magazines and serials that do not contain any article directly related to Brodsky. Some serials include articles on Russian culture or literature that do not mention Brodsky.
  - Clippings related to Brodsky
    - Clippings, 1964-1983 (Box 177, Folder 3823-3843)
    - Clippings, 1984-1990 (Box 178, Folder 3844-3858)
    - Clippings, 1991-1996 (Box 179, Folder 3859-3873)
    - Clippings, 1997-2003, undated (Box 180, Folder 3874-3885)
  - Other Clippings, 1972-1979
  - Other Clippings, 1980-1993
  - Other Clippings, 1994-2002
- Printed Material, circa 1920-2003; Series IX; 2.04; (8 boxes)
  The Series is organized into two subseries: Copies of Articles and Ephemera. Copies of Articles is arranged alphabetically by author. Ephemera is further organized under two headings: Ephemera related to Brodsky and Other Ephemera. Ephemera is arranged chronologically under each heading.
  Copies of articles consist of photocopies from journals and volumes related to literature, primarily poetry. Many of the articles relate to topics and poets of particular interest to Brodsky, such as Constantine Cavafy and Marina Tsvetaeva. Ephemera includes posters, flyers, catalogs and postcards. Ephemera Related to Brodsky documents Brodsky's poetry readings, appearances and publications as well as memorials, exhibits and other events dedicated to Brodsky. Other Ephemera includes blank postcards, catalogs from exhibitions that Brodsky may have attended, and publisher's catalogs that do not include Brodsky's writings.
  - Copies of Articles
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - "A"-"D", 1978-2001, undated (Box 181, Folder 3886-3906)
    - "E"-"M", 1971-1999, undated (Box 182, Folder 3907-3938)
    - "M" continued -"S", 1967-2000, undated (Box 183, Folder 3939-3976)
    - "T"-"Z", 1972-2000, undated (Box 184, Folder 3977-3995)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 184, Folder 3996-4002)
      Includes Brodsky's "collection of little poems [of others] for postcards; never used."
  - Ephemera
    - Ephemera related to Brodsky
      - 1972-1996 (Box 185, Folder 4003-4034)
      - 1997-2003 (Box 186, Folder 4035-4039)
        Consists of material that documents memorials to Brodsky and a set of postcards printed with photographs of Brodsky.
      - Undated (Box 186, Folder 4040-4044)
        Includes two matchbooks printed with photographs of Brodsky and posters publicizing undated readings and other appearances.
      - Posters, 1987-1990, 1987-1990, undated (Box 4044a)
    - Other ephemera
      - Circa 1920-1991, circa 1920-10991 (Box 186, Folder 4045-4057)
      - 1992-2000 (Box 187, Folder 4058-4066)
      - Undated (Box 187, Folder 4067-4071)
  - Nobel Prize Series. Joseph Brodsky: Poet between empires. Teacher Resource Book, four copies, 1990 (Box 242)
    For related videocassette, see box 172, GENMSS613_0009.
- Artwork, 1972-1986, undated; Series X; 0.21; (1 box)
  Drawings by Brodsky and small printed artwork found in Brodsky's homes and offices is filed in Series V, Personal Papers.
  Artwork is arranged roughly according to medium.
  The series consists of artwork of a variety of genres that was in Brodsky's homes and office. The material includes prints of engravings, sketches, posters and paintings. Several of the original works were given to Brodsky by the artists, as evidenced by inscriptions.
  - Still life, pencil sketch, 1984 (Box 188, Folder 4072)
    Inscribed "From Brighton with love. T. to J."
  - Portrait of Brodsky, photocopy of a sketch, 1986 (Box 188, Folder 4073)
  - Portrait of Brodsky and still life, pastel, undated (Box 188, Folder 4074)
  - Three nude women, pencil sketch, undated
    Inscribed to Brodsky "I will never turn to women."
  - Two posters by Sonia Delaunay, prints, 1977
  - Posters, prints, undated (Box 4074a)
  - "Autumn in Norenskaya," monoprint by Piotr Kasprzak, 1988 (Box 4074b)
  - New Yorker cartoon, print, 1986
  - "Hommage to Northampton," ink, undated
  - Singel, Amsterdam, aquatint by Karel Kok, 1980
  - Stanhope Hotel in New York, watercolor by Barker, 1979
  - Abstract painting "for Brodsky," watercolor, 1993
  - "The Winter Palace in St. Petersburg," engraving by Warren, 1972? (Box 188, Folder 4075)
    Inscribed to Brodsky "Christmas [1972?]"
  - Nude figure lying down, engraving by [J___ K___?], 1974 (Box 188, Folder 4076)
  - "The battle of Waterloo," engraving drawn by De Neuville and engraved by Outhwaite, undated (Box 188, Folder 4077)
  - "Ovid," engraving by Desrochers, undated
  - "A view of the Exchange and the warehouses at Petersburg in Russia," engraving, undated
  - "Vue de L'Amiraute ed de des environs," engraving by Niquet, undated
  - "Les Centaures," engraving by Stagnon, undated
  - View of Venice, etching, undated
  - Abstract image "for Joseph Brodsky," etching, undated
  - Illustrations of Greek mythology from an unidentified printed volume, pages 224, 289, 293, undated (Box 188, Folder 4078)
  - Illustrations of Triton and unidentified woman from an unidentified printed volume, pages 289 and 313, undated (Box 188, Folder 4079)
  - Streetscapes, photocopies of engravings, undated (Box 188, Folder 4080)
  - Artwork Deborah Frizelli, drawings and oil painting, 1985, undated (Box 188, Folder 4081)
    Includes a note from Frizelli to Brodsky that formerly accompanied the oil painting, which depicts a chair.
  - "The cane," by J.S., pastel, undated (Box 188, Folder 4082)
  - "Mars," photograph, undated
- Papers of Others, 1912-2000; Series XI; 2.09; (5 boxes)
  The Series is organized into four Subseries: Masha Vorobiov Papers, Carl and Ellendea Proffer Papers, George Kline Papers and Others.
  The series consists of papers sent to Ann Kjellberg to be included in Brodsky's archive.
  Masha Vorobiov was a friend of Brodsky and sometimes acted as assistant and translator. She taught Russian Language and Literature at Vassar College from 1977-2000 and died in 2001 at the age of 67. Carl and Ellendea Proffer founded Ardis Press in Ann Arbor Michigan and were instrumental in publishing much of Brodsky's Russian-language poetry in the United States. George Kline taught at Bryn Mawr College and translated several of Brodsky's poems from Russian to English.
  - Masha Vorobiov Papers
    Masha Vorobiov Papers are organized under four headings: Correspondence, Writings, Printed Material and Other Papers.
    Masha Vorobiov contributed substantially to the archive of Brodsky's correspondence and writings. Material of Brodsky's that was in Vorobiov's possession is interfiled in Series I. Writings and Series II. Correspondence. This subseries consists of Voribiov's own papers, most of which relate to Brodsky.
    Masha Voribiov Papers include correspondence, notes and photocopies of articles. Correspondence is incoming unless otherwise indicated. Most correspondence relates to the publication of Brodsky's writings or events dedicated to Brodsky. Notes are more personal in nature and include phone numbers, addresses, travel itineraries and medical information. Printed material includes photocopies of journal articles and book excerpts related to Brodsky and to literature generally.
    - Correspondence
      Arranged alphabetically. Unidentified correspondence is filed at the end of the listing.
      - "A" general, 1974-1996 (Box 189, Folder 4083)
      - Blane, Andrew, undated (Box 189, Folder 4084)
      - Brodskii, Aleksandr and Mariia, 1975? (Box 189, Folder 4085)
      - Chukovskii, Kornei, 1967, 1999, undated (Box 189, Folder 4086)
        Includes newspaper clippings related to Kornei Chukovskii.
      - Consul General of France, 1991-1992 (Box 189, Folder 4087)
      - Gordin, Iakov, 1997 (Box 189, Folder 4088)
      - International Freedom to Publish Committee, 1981 (Box 189, Folder 4089)
      - Jackson, M., 1996 (Box 189, Folder 4090)
      - Joseph Brodsky Memorial Fellowship Fund, 1999 (Box 189, Folder 4091)
      - Katilius, Ramunas, 2001 (Box 189, Folder 4092)
      - Kjellberg, Ann, incoming and outgoing, 1996-2000 (Box 189, Folder 4093-4094)
      - Klimoff, Liza, 1976? (Box 189, Folder 4095)
      - Kline, George, 1970 (Box 189, Folder 4096)
      - Limonov, Eduard, outgoing, 1984 (Box 189, Folder 4097)
      - Loseff, Lev, 1981-1996 (Box 189, Folder 4098)
      - Meiselas, Nancy, 1977 (Box 189, Folder 4099)
      - Muchnic, Helen, outgoing, 1994-1997 (Box 189, Folder 4100)
      - Novodvorskaia, Irina, 1997 (Box 189, Folder 4101)
      - Novyi Zhurnal, 1992 (Box 189, Folder 4102)
      - Picken, Margo, incoming and outgoing, 1978-1996 (Box 189, Folder 4103)
      - Polukhina, Valentina, 1981 (Box 189, Folder 4104)
        Includes a photocopy of a letter from Dmitrii Savitskii to Richard Berns.
      - Proffer, Carl, 1974 (Box 189, Folder 4105)
      - Rubin, Barry and Lydia, undated (Box 189, Folder 4106)
      - Russian Academy in Rome, 1996 (Box 189, Folder 4107)
        Includes notes and financial papers.
      - Straus, Roger and [Dorothea], 1979-1980 (Box 189, Folder 4108)
      - Simon and Schuster, inc., 1997 (Box 189, Folder 4109)
      - Unidentified, 1992-1999, undated (Box 189, Folder 4110)
    - Notes
      Arranged roughly chronologically.
      - 1973-1989 (Box 189, Folder 4111-4118)
      - 1990-2000 (Box 190, Folder 4119-4130)
      - Undated (Box 190, Folder 4131-4140)
    - Visitor register [for Brodsky's memorial service?], 1996? (Box 190, Folder 4141-4142)
    - Printed material
      Arranged alphabetically by author. Articles with unidentified authors are filed at the end of the listing.
      - "A"-"G", 1973-1996, undated (Box 190, Folder 4143-4151)
      - "H"-"Z", 1973-1996, undated (Box 191, Folder 4152-4188)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 191, Folder 4189)
  - Carl and Ellendea Proffer Papers
    Carl and Ellendea Proffer Papers include correspondence, notes and newspaper clippings. Correspondence (incoming and outgoing) relates to Ardis Press, Russian Literature Triquarterly and to Vladimir Maramzin. Notes relate to Carl Proffer's translations of Brodsky's works. Material related to the campaign to release Vladimir Maramzin from prison in the Soviet Union includes open letters, newspaper clippings and a transcript of Maramzin's trial in 1974. Maramzin was imprisoned on charges related to the compilation Joseph Brodsky's writings and to the distribution of Maramzin's own writings.
    - Correspondence
      - "A"-"H" general, 1972-1980, undated (Box 192, Folder 4190)
      - Hall, Donald, 1973 (Box 192, Folder 4191)
      - "K" general, 1972, undated (Box 192, Folder 4192)
      - Kiselev, Alexey, 1975 (Box 192, Folder 4193)
      - Kline, George, 1970-1972 (Box 192, Folder 4194)
      - Levine, Madeline, 1979 (Box 192, Folder 4195)
      - Litvinova, Tatiana, 1972 (Box 192, Folder 4196)
      - Mandelshtam, Nadezhda, 1973 (Box 192, Folder 4197)
      - Murphy, Irene, 1972-1973 (Box 192, Folder 4198)
      - Myers, Priscilla, 1973-1974 (Box 192, Folder 4199)
      - New York Review of Books, 1973-1974 (Box 192, Folder 4200)
      - "P" general, 1973-1978 (Box 192, Folder 4201)
      - Poetry, 1974 (Box 192, Folder 4202)
      - "R" general, 1975 (Box 192, Folder 4203)
      - "S", 1975-1976 (Box 192, Folder 4204)
      - Silvers, Robert
        See: New York Review of Books
      - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1974 (Box 192, Folder 4205)
      - "T" general, 1972 (Box 192, Folder 4206)
      - "U" general, 1974 (Box 192, Folder 4207)
      - University of Michigan, 1972-1980 (Box 192, Folder 4208)
      - Updike, John, 1972 (Box 192, Folder 4209)
      - Verheul, Kees, 1974 (Box 192, Folder 4210)
      - Viereck, Peter, 1973 (Box 192, Folder 4211)
      - Volkov, Solomon, 1982 (Box 192, Folder 4212)
      - Vorobiov, Masha, 1974 (Box 192, Folder 4213)
        Includes a draft of "A declaration by Vladimir Maramzin."
      - "W" general, 1972-1974 (Box 192, Folder 4214)
      - Wilbur, Richard, 1973-1974 (Box 192, Folder 4215)
      - Yeo, Mr., 1974 (Box 192, Folder 4216)
      - Unidentified, 1972-1983, undated (Box 192, Folder 4217)
        Includes an undated letter to "V." with attached photocopies of Brodsky's essay "On Richard Wilbur" and poem Sonnet.
    - Broadside, unidentified author, occasional poem to Joseph Brodsky, undated (Box 192, Folder 4218)
      Begins "Dear Joseph Brodsky, Russian friend and dear/ To mourn and celebrate we gather here." Written for the occasion of Brodsky's departure from Michigan.
    - Notes, undated (Box 192, Folder 4219-4220)
      Includes notes on Carl Proffer's English translation of Sonnet, an unidentified poem and an unidentified prose writing.
    - Press releases about Joseph Brodsky, 1972? (Box 192, Folder 4221)
    - Campaign to release Vladimir Maramzin, 1974-1975 (Box 192, Folder 4222-4230)
  - George Kline Papers